KELLI KING

Hilliard, OH

Phone: 614.352.8950| Email: 22.kelliking@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kelli-king-4344254/

GitHub: https://github.com/thorgriffs Portfolio: https://github.com/thorgriffs/portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with 15 years of IT experience in all phases of software development, from high level project scoping and requirements definition to production releases. Solid skills in agile project management, release management, business analysis, quality assurance, and production support. Effective at prioritizing, planning, and delivering technology initiatives with an emphasis on teamwork and customer service.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, SQL

Applications: GitHub, SQL Server Mgmt Studio, PostgreSQL, JIRA, IntelliJ IDEA, MySQL,

MongoDB

Tools: Bootstrap, Node, Express, Handlebars

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Sedgwick Manager, IT Service Delivery & Relationship

Dublin, OH

Apr 2018 – Present

Manager on an app development team with responsibilities for Iteration Management, Release Management, Quality Assurance, and Production Support

- Manage all phases of SDLC including high level solution scoping, requirements elicitation, development, testing, production release, and ongoing application support
- Interface with business operations team to prioritize product backlog and coordinate delivery timelines
- Oversee operational support for ongoing application issue resolution and end user training opportunities

IT Manager, Quality Assurance & Business Analysis

Apr 2017 - Mar 2018

Manager on an app development team with responsibilities for Iteration Management, Release Management, Quality Assurance, and Production Support

- Manage all phases of SDLC including high level solution scoping, requirements elicitation, development, testing, production release, and ongoing application support
- Interface with business operations team to prioritize product backlog and coordinate delivery timelines
- Oversee operational support for ongoing application issue resolution and end user training opportunities

BA/QA Analyst

Oct 2014 - Apr 2017

Analyst on a small app dev team responsible for Iteration management, user story creation, quality assurance testing, and production support

- Elicit requirements from business operations team to generate user stories and product backlog
- Write and execute test cases for internal and client facing web applications
- Manage application release list and approval process
- Provide support for UAT team
- Troubleshoot production support issues

BPL Global (now Connected Energy) Quality Assurance Analyst

Dublin, OH Mar 2010 - Dec 2013

- Participated in user story development, work estimation, backlog prioritization, sprint planning, and sprint retrospective in Agile software development environment
- Wrote and executed test cases for web and client/server applications
- Constructed Gherkin feature files for TDD/SBE automated testing of application service and UI layers in IntelliJ IDEA
- Collaborated with product owner, business analyst and software development team to create product acceptance criteria
- Queried data in data warehouse and application databases in SQL (SQL Server Mgmt Studio), PostgreSQL (pgAdmin), and MongoDB (MongoVUE) environments.
- Constructed test datasets utilizing both real and simulated data
- Worked closely with Development team to identify, reproduce, and isolate defects
- Reported and tracked system defects in JIRA bug tracking system
- Set up and upgraded test environments consisting of software, firmware, and testing tools

Resource Interactive (now IBM iX) Quality Assurance Tester

Columbus, OH Dec 2009 - Mar 201

- Executed functional, regression, metric, accessibility, and ad hoc testing for Resource Interactive client web applications
- Communicated with Development and Project Management teams regarding system requirements clarification
- Reported and tracked system defects in JIRA bug tracking system
- Created and maintained test case documentation for progress tracking purposes
- Identified and communicated the impact of testing issues and defects to Project Management team

e-Play Quality Assurance Tester

Columbus, OH Aug 2009 - Nov 2010

- Created and maintained test scripts for manual testing of e-Play's DVD vending kiosks and online reservation system
- Executed tests (system, GUI functionality, stress, and regression) and logged defects
- Reported and tracked system defects in FogBugz issue tracking system
- Communicated with development team regarding build specifications, issue resolution, and test reporting
- Contributed to and reviewed release test plans
- Performed ad hoc testing as necessary for e-Play's internal customer service and technical support application

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bellatore Financial Senior Relationship Manager

San Jose, CA Oct 2008 - Apr 2009

- Acted as front line of contact for service and support to the firm's independent Registered Investment Advisor clientele
- Provided day to day operations and account management support
- Delivered front office application training and support to on-boarding and current advisor clients
- Provided generalist level support of advisor business development needs
- Assisted in the development and implementation of department policies and procedures

 Coordinated and monitored the transition of accounts from the Nationwide Advisory Services Program

Nationwide Financial Services Analyst

Dublin, OH July 2007 - Sept 2008

- Acted as front line of contact for service and support to the firm's independent registered investment advisor clientele
- Provided day to day operations and account management support
- Delivered front office application training and support to on boarding and current advisor clients
- Acted as liaison between back office and advisor clientele
- Assisted in the testing and migration of new system implementations for improved end user experience
- Reviewed daily processing transactions for quality control
- Provided support as needed to Advisory Services Program Internal Wholesale department
- Coordinated and monitored the transition of accounts to Bellatore Financial

BISYS Fund Services (now Citigroup) Quality Analyst, IT

Columbus, OH July 2002 - June 2007

- Worked with the business unit to determine a project's testing time frame, scope, requirements, risks, duties and deliverables
- Created and maintained testing documentation consisting of plans, scripts, test and issue tracking documents for all business units and systems impacted
- Coordinated and tracked testing timelines with external system vendors as needed
- Identified and communicated the impact and expected resolution of testing issues to end users and other appropriate parties
- Provided corporate training department with documentation and procedure updates related to application and system enhancements

Senior Dealer Services Associate

- Reviewed and processed failed broker/dealer mutual fund transactions transmitted via Fund/SERV and ACATS systems
- Acted as primary contact for brokerage back office personnel regarding account transaction posting
- Reviewed, maintained, and distributed time-sensitive daily transaction files within all internal Transfer Agency departments
- Provided end user online account system training and support
- Resolved file transmission errors between broker/dealers and BISYS
- Supported the business unit with mutual fund mass mergers and conversions

Shareholder Services Associate

- Assisted prospective investors, shareholders, brokers and institutional clients with mutual fund account inquiries
- Processed telephone initiated purchase, redemption and exchange orders
- Resolved system errors related to fund direct account transactions
- Reviewed daily processing transactions for quality control

EDUCATION

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH Certificate - Coding Bootcamp, April 2021

Columbus State Community College, Columbus, OH Coursework for Certificate of Accounting, January 2007 - September 2008

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH Bachelor of Arts - Comparative Studies in Religion, June 2001